Dav(id|e|o)? Watson

Creating software in products, services, and tools from ideas to code, data to science, and dialog boxes to documentation.

Summary

Flexible individuals yield agile teams. A **computer science** award and a **computer programming** internship bookended music school. Beyond college, <u>cofounded a startup</u>, joined <u>MAYA</u>, and crafted software as an employee and later a stakeholder for a decade. Design thinking flowed from ideas, prototypes, and tools that shaped product development and service deployment.

Experience

Wyvern ### 2023-2024

Technical Consultant (1099) Nashua, NH

Software Architecture, IT Practice, and theory around Deno, Docker Compose, Kubernetes, Node, TypeScript, and beyond

Freelance

2022

Design Engineer Pittsburgh, PA

Prototyped concepts on Personal Knowledge Management around <u>GPT</u> with my friend from <u>Catapult</u>

Caterpillar 🜐 2021

Technical Consultant (1099) Pittsburgh, PA

Built C++/GCC/Linux code ported from Intel to ZCU-104 MPSoC using FPGA compiler flags for 20%-50% better performance

Carnegie Mellon University (Emerging Technology Center)

Senior Member of Technical Staff Pittsburgh, PA

• Artificial Intelligence (AI), Human Computer Interaction (HCI), High Performance Computing (HPC)

Caterpillar ⊕ 2018-2020

Software Engineering Specialist (W-2)

Pittsburgh, PA

- Assembled Sensor Storage for Edge Network on Kubernetes using Python 3, Minio, and PostgreSQL with a team of 4 engineers
- Collaborated with 12 IT execs on planning and long-term implications of hyperconverged infrastructure on cloud native storage

Rent Jungle (RainMaker (RealPage))

Senior Software Engineer

2016-2018 Pittsburgh, PA

2020

- Led weekly retro to 2x better cadence, communication, velocity, and teamwork
- Crafted Scrapy/Tor (python 3) crawler on Django, PostgreSQL, Kubernetes

VP Product Development, IT Compliance Officer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Led 4-person interdisciplinary design team through Ember SPA MVP designed and delivered in collaboration with MAYA Design
- Developed API backend on Python 3 <u>Django REST Framework</u>, PostgreSQL emitting JSON API to Ember SPA on Aptible

Hire an Esquire (Major, Lindsey, and Africa) 🌐

2014

VP Engineering Pittsburgh, PA

- Led a team of 6 through a lean Python 3 redesign and refactoring of the entire UI/UX from legacy MVP Django system
- Reduced daily production firefighting by more than 50% using nimble methods, automated tests, CI/CD, code and design review

Forever

2013-2014

Senior Software Developer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Prototyped full-stack (Bootstrap to Heroku) cloud idea in 2 weeks on Python 3 before porting MVP from Python to Ruby on Rails
- Enabled the company to capture strong market traction in under a year after releasing 1.0 e-commerce platform finished at Neo

SMaSh - Brainstorm SMS Technologies (Mind Matrix)



2011 - 2012

Senior Engineer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Wrote conversational text systems (like twilio) in Python/PostgreSQL
- Supported large SMS text campaigns from Pittsburgh Steelers to Miller-Coors

2010-2011

Software Development Manager

Pittsburgh, PA

- Responsible for Sophia and Flintbox product development, deployment, and support
- Led team of 12 from slow legacy data center of > 1M SLOC to fast, automated SaaS virtualization of CI/CD, DevOps, and SRE
- Prototyped systems using Capistrano (Ruby), Mechanize (Python), and Selenium with team of 4-7 software engineers

Applied Perception (Foster Miller (Qinetiq))

2008-2009

Project Engineer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Visualized XML sonar data in python backend/C++ GUI application on Windows
- Ported Microsoft C#.net Windows GUI to C++/Qt/Linux for OCU deployment

NOMOS (North American Scientific, Best Medical) @

2006-2007

UI Software Engineer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Coded C++ QA tests and maintained Perl code review system on CORVUS FDA-regulated radiotherapy product with team of 12-16
- Prototyped wireframes and rendered storyboards in C++/Python2/Qt for adaptive 4D treatment planning with team of 4

MAYA Design (BCG) @

2004-2006

Software Design Engineer

Pittsburgh, PA

- Deployed python web services emitting JSON to JDA clients on team of 4 developing A+ Schools, 3RC, DHS to win an award
- Demoed GUI lighting IoT Zigbee PoC in C#.net/COM/Visio on Windows for Phillips execs in 5 days sketch-to-code

Cobind @

2003-2004 Pittsburgh, PA

Cofounder

Borrowed cobind concept from research signifying binding an app with its OS cooperatively and declaratively (like embedded)

- At the time, Redpath, Suse, and Timesys could build custom linux, albeit embedded. Spoke to Ian Murdock about Progeny too
- Collaborated on Linux Tools startup with cofounder and consultant. Received worldwide press after Idea Foundry Fellowship

Education

BSBA

Coursework

Computer Science, Music Education, Systems Analysis, Technical Writing

Passion Fasting, Reading, Writing, Running, and Feasting